sunjournal.com 2011-05-27

# Privacy Policy | Sun Journal

This online privacy policy pertains to all Sun Media Group affiliated websites including but not limited to websites for Sun Journal, The Forecaster, Sun Press, The Bethel Citizen, The Rumford Falls Times, Advertiser Democrat, The Franklin Journal, Livermore Falls Advertiser, The Rangeley Highlander, The Penobscot Times and Employment Times, hereinafter referred to as "SunJournal.com".

SunJournal.com is committed to protecting consumer privacy online. We believe that greater protection of personal privacy on the Web will not only protect consumers, but also increase consumer confidence and ultimately their participation in online activities. At SunJournal.com, we intend to give you as much control as possible over your personal information.

The purpose of our policy is to inform you about the types of information we gather about you when you visit our site(s), how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to correct, the information.

Our site(s) may contain links to other Web sites, including Web sites directed to children. We have no control over the privacy practices or the content of any of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors or other sites to which we provide links from our sites. You should check the applicable privacy policy of the Web site sponsor when linking to other Web sites.

I. Membership and Registration

If you become a Member of SunJournal.com, you accept responsibility for all activities that occur under your account or password, and agree not to sell, transfer or assign your Membership or any Membership rights. We reserve the right to terminate your Membership at any time for any reason. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password and for restricting access to your computer so others outside your household may not access SunJournal.com using your name in whole or in part without our permission. If you believe someone has accessed SunJournal.com using your member name and password without your authorization, e-mail us immediately at [webmaster@sunjournal.com](mailto:webmaster@sunjournal.com).

Some areas within our network of sites may require a credit card payment before access is granted. If you sign up for these services, you agree to pay all subscription fees and any other charges incurred in connection with your member name and password (including any applicable taxes) at the rates in effect when the charges were incurred. We may bill charges automatically to your credit card. All fees will be billed at the beginning of your subscription or any renewal (or as soon thereafter as fees or charges are incurred) and are nonrefundable. You are responsible for all fees and charges incurred to access SunJournal.com through an Internet access provider or other third party service. Your subscription will renew automatically, unless we terminate it or you notify us by e-mail of your decision to terminate your subscription. You must cancel your subscription before it renews in order to avoid billing of fees for the renewal term to your credit card.

II. Miscellaneous

SunJournal.com reserves the right to change these Terms of Service at any time in its discretion and to notify users of any such changes solely by changing this Terms of Service. Your continued use of SunJournal.com after the posting of any amended Terms of Service shall constitute your agreement to be bound by any such changes. Your use of this site prior to the time this Terms of Service was posted will be governed according to the Terms of Service that applied at the time of your use.

SunJournal.com may modify, suspend, discontinue or restrict the use of any portion of SunJournal.com, including the availability of any portion of the Content at any time, without notice or liability.  SunJournal.com may deny access to any person or user at any time for any reason. In addition, SunJournal.com may at any time transfer rights and obligations under this Agreement to any subsidiary or business unit, or any of their affiliated companies or divisions, or any entity that acquires SunJournal.com or any of their assets.

These Terms of Service will be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of Maine, without regard to its conflicts of law provisions. You hereby agree that any cause of action you may have with respect to SunJournal.com must be filed in a federal or state court located in Lewiston, Maine, within two months of the time in which the events giving rise to such claim began, or you agree to waive such claim. You agree no such claim may be brought as a class action. If for any reason any provision of this Agreement is found unenforceable, that provision shall be enforced to the maximum extent permissible so as to affect the intent of the parties as reflected in that provision, and the remainder of the Agreement shall continue in full force and effect. Any failure of SunJournal.com to enforce or exercise any provision of this Agreement or related right shall not constitute a waiver of that right or provision. The section titles used in this Agreement are purely for convenience and carry with them no legal or contractual effect. In the event of termination of this Agreement for any reason, you agree the following provisions will survive: the provisions regarding limitations on your use of Content, the license(s) you have granted to SunJournal.com, and all other provisions for which survival is equitable or appropriate.

In the case of a conflict between these terms and the terms of any electronic or machine readable statement or policy (for example, a P3P electronic privacy policy), these Terms of Service shall control. Similarly, in case of a conflict between these terms and our Privacy Policy stated below, these Terms of Service control.

III. PRIVACY POLICY

SunJournal.com strives to offer its visitors the many advantages of Internet technology and to provide an interactive and personalized experience. We may use Personally Identifiable Information (your name, e-mail address, street address, telephone number and other information) subject to the terms of this privacy policy. Please note this policy applies only to information collected by SunJournal.com online and does not impact information collected or used by SunJournal.com or its affiliates through other means.

IV. How we gather information from users

How we collect and store information depends on the page you are visiting, the activities in which you elect to participate and the services provided. You can visit many pages on our site without providing any information. Other pages may prompt you to provide information, such as when you register for access to portions of our site, sign up for membership, request certain features (e.g., newsletters, news updates and other products), sign up for a newspaper subscription or make a purchase. You may also provide information when you participate in sweepstakes and contests, voting and polling activities, message boards and chat rooms and other interactive areas of our site.

Like most Web sites, SunJournal.com also collects information automatically and through the use of electronic tools that may be transparent to our visitors. For example, we may log the name of your Internet Service Provider or use "cookie" technology. Among other things, the cookie may store your user name and password, sparing you from having to re-enter that information each time you visit, or may control the number of times you encounter a particular advertisement while visiting our site. As we adopt additional technology, we may also gather information through other means. In certain cases, you can choose not to provide us with information, for example by setting your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but doing so may limit your ability to access certain portions of the site or may require you to re-enter your user name and password. Additionally we may not be able to customize the site's features according to your preferences.

V. What we do with the information we collect

We will use your information only as permitted by law. Aggregated Information (information that does not personally identify you) may be used in many ways. As one example, we may combine information about your usage patterns with similar information obtained from other users to learn which pages are visited most or what features are most attractive. Aggregated Information may occasionally be shared with our advertisers and business partners, but cannot be used to contact you individually.

We also collect information to enhance your visit and deliver more individualized content and advertising. For example, we may use Personally Identifiable Information collected on SunJournal.com to communicate with you regarding our Terms of Service and privacy policy, products and services offered by SunJournal.com and other affiliates and partners, administration of sweepstakes and contests, processing e-commerce transactions and other topics we think you might find of interest. We reserve the right to share this information with other business units and affiliates, including for example our affiliated newspapers and entities which has an ownership interest (collectively, "Affiliates"). This policy does not apply to any Affiliate's use of such information.

Personally Identifiable Information collected by SunJournal.com may also be used for other purposes including but not limited to site administration and troubleshooting. Certain third parties who provide technical support for the operation of our site (our classifieds service and our automotive solution provider, for example) may access such information.

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also disclose your information in response to a court order, at other times when we believe we are reasonably required to do so by law, in connection with the collection of amounts you may owe to us, and/or whenever we deem it appropriate or necessary to give such information to law enforcement authorities. Please note we may not provide you with notice prior to disclosure in such cases.

VI. Affiliated sites, linked sites and advertisements

SunJournal.com expects its partners, advertisers and third-party affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. However, third parties, including our partners, advertisers, affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may link to, or view as part of a frame on a SunJournal.com page, certain content that is actually created or hosted by a third party. Also, through SunJournal.com you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, Web sites, advertisements, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties.  SunJournal.com is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

While on our site, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. For example, some of our advertising is served by third parties and may include cookies that enable the advertiser to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before. Through features available on our site, third parties may use cookies or other technology to gather information.  SunJournal.com does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online. Should you choose to voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information on our site, such as in message boards, chat areas or in advertising or notices you post, that information can be viewed publicly and can be collected and used by third parties without our knowledge and may result in unsolicited messages from other individuals or third parties. Such activities are beyond the control of SunJournal.com and this policy.

VII. Children

SunJournal.com does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under the age of 13 except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under the age of 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe SunJournal.com has any information from or about anyone under the age of 13, please contact us at [webmaster@SunJournal.com](mailto:webmaster@SunJournal.com).

VIII. Disclosure to Third Parties

We do not share personal identifying information with any third party without your permission. We disclose only in aggregate form our statistical analyses or demographics of users to third parties, such as advertisers or other business partners. In some instances, we operate shared Web sites with businesses affiliated with us. Our privacy policy will apply to these Web sites, and our affiliates adhere to our privacy policy and will not share personal information with any third party without your permission. PLEASE BE AWARE that when you voluntarily disclose personal information (such as your name, e-mail address) in chat areas or bulletin boards to third parties, that information may be collected by others outside the control of us and may result in unsolicited messages from others.

IX. Accuracy of User Information

In order to ensure the accuracy of personal information provided for registration, you may return to the registration form online in order to change information you have provided at any time. Questions regarding our privacy policy, the accuracy of your personal information or the use of the information collected should be directed via e-mail to [webmaster@SunJournal.com](mailto:webmaster@SunJournal.com), or you can reach us by telephone in at 207-784-5411. You can also write us at:

SunJournal.com

P.O. Box  4400

Lewiston, Maine 04 243-4400

These privacy policies are effective as of April 28, 2009. We reserve the right to change this policy at any time, and will post any changes to this policy as soon as they go into effect.

X. Security of Information

We use our best efforts to ensure the security of personal information submitted by users. When collecting credit card information for online purchases, we offer secured-server transactions that encrypt your information in transit to thwart someone from intercepting it and misusing it. When we collect other information from our users, it is stored in an area where the general public does not have access to it.

XI. Use of Materials

The right to download and store or output the materials in our site(s) is granted for the user's personal use only, and materials may not be reproduced in any edited form. Any other reproduction, transmission, performance, display or editing of these materials by any means mechanical or electronic without the express written permission of us is strictly prohibited. Users wishing to obtain permission to reprint or reproduce any materials appearing on these sites may contact us via e-mail at: [feedback@SunJournal.com](mailto:feedback@SunJournal.com).
